Guide to the Papers of Harrison Salisbury,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Box Listing (unsorted)
  - T: -- To and from Salisbury. From Evan Thomas (W. W. Norton, with copies of exchange between Thomas and Clark Clifford) -- Copies of Salisbury to Y. Tsedenbal (Premier, Mongolia), Times Literary Supplement -- File on World Press Institute (James Toscano) -- Salisbury or talk, "The Origins of the Cold War in Asia", 1971 (Box 550, Folder 25)
  - U: To and from Salisbury. Including from Stewart Udall, 1971 (Box 550, Folder 26)
  - V: -- To and from Salisbury. From Jack Valenti (MPAA), Jean Vanden Heuvel, Laurens Van der Post, Sam Vaughn (Publisher, Doubleday), Viking Press, 1971 (Box 550, Folder 27)
  - W: -- To and from Salisbury. From De Witt Wallace (readers Digest), Richard J. and Mary O. Walsh (John Day CO., Publishers), Jay Waltz (New York Times, Ottawa), Frederic Warburg (Martin Secker and Warburg, Publishers, London), Francis Warner (ST. Peter's College, Oxford), Aline (Mrs. Alec) Werth, Sidney Whelan (VP, American Museum of Natural History), Theodore H. White (copies -- re Visiting Committee for the Department of History, Harvard), Alan D. Williams (Editorial director, Viking Press), World Press Institute, Herman Wouk. One in German and photocopied pages in German, 1971 (Box 550, Folder 28)
  - Whitney, Thomas P. Julia Whitney Foundation: Some in Russian, 1971, (Financial Statements, Correspondence ) (Box 550, Folder 29)
  - Wiltwyck Fundraising for Wiltwyck School for Boys: To and from Salisbury. Including copies of Salisbury to: Walter Cronkite, Tom Whitney, Arthur Ochs Sulzberger, Iphigene Ochs Sulzberger, Irvin Taubkin, Ada Louise Huxtable (similar materials appear in many other folders), 1971, (Letters ) (Box 550, Folder 30)
  - XY: -- To and from Salisbury. Including from Genevieve Young (J. P. Lippincott), 1971 (Box 550, Folder 31)
  - Z: To and from Salisbury. Including from Jerrold Zacharias (MIT), 1971, (Letter, Mss., Op-ed ) (Box 550, Folder 32)
  - Soviet Union: -- WWII Project: Salisbury from University of Minnesota Foundation re Soviet WWII project from Sonja Erikson (Salisbury' secretary) to Ralph Nader, SeN. Edward Brooke, Boston Globe requesting material for (Eloquence of Protest), 1971, (Memoir, Letter, Book ) (Box 550, Folder 33)
  - Richardson Merrell Annual Report, Internal Memos, 1971 (Box 550, Folder 34)
  - T: -- To and from Salisbury. Of Travel and Leisure, and cables to and from Truman family re death of Harry S Truman, 1972 (Box 551, Folder 21)
  - U: To and from Salisbury. From Edward Carlson (President, United Airlines), 1972 (Box 551, Folder 22)
  - V: To and from Salisbury. From Ivan Veit (Executive Vice President, New York Times), 1972 (Box 551, Folder 23)
  - W: -- To and from Salisbury. From De Witt Wallace (Readers Digest), Lee Williams (Administrative Assistant to SeN. J. W. Fulbright), Helen Wolff (Helen and Kurt Wolff, Harcourt, Brace, Jovanovich), WOR Radio, World Press Institute, 1972 (Box 551, Folder 24)
  - XYZ: -- To and from Salisbury. From Michael Burke (Chairman and President, NY Yankees), Daniel Yankelovich, InC., Daniel Yergin -- Copy of Salisbury to Arnold Zohn (Arno Press), 1972 (Box 551, Folder 25)
  - Salisbury New York Times Confidential: Mostly to Salisbury and re Op-ed, (Internal Memos ) (Box 551, Folder 26)
  - National Committee, 1972 (Box 551, Folder 27)
  - Op-Ed Task Force, (Memos ) (Box 551, Folder 28)
  - Russell Sage College: re Salisbury visiting professorship, Spring 1972, 1972, (Correspondence ) (Box 551, Folder 29)
  - New York Times Service Material Task Force, (Memos ) (Box 551, Folder 30)
  - Julia Whitney Foundation, 1972, (Correspondence ) (Box 551, Folder 31)
  - Wiltwyck Wiltwyck School for Boys: re contributions, 1972, (Letters ) (Box 551, Folder 32)
  - New York Times Youth Task Force: re improving Times coverage of and appeal to youth, (Memos, Notes, Meeting Minutes ) (Box 551, Folder 33)
  - Movie Project: re possible Italian TV documentary of Orbit of China -- Including from Thondup, the Chogyal of Sikkim -- renato Pochetti (Executive VP, RAI) -- Copies of Salisbury to Kim II Sung, Ne Win (Burma), (Letters, Telegrams, Script ) (Box 551, Folder 34)
  - Halperin Case: re Halperin V. New York Times, (Letters, Memos ) (Box 552, Folder 1)
  - Hamilton-Merritt Beyond the Bittersweet: Multiple copies or versions of some chapters, 1973, (Letters, Mss. ) (Box 552, Folder 2)
  - National Committee, 1973 (Box 552, Folder 3)
  - Korea: -- To and from Salisbury. Including from and to government officials in North and South Korea (Box 552, Folder 4)
  - Reston Memos, Cable: Cable from James B. Reston to Salisbury and others (Box 552, Folder 5)
  - Salisbury, Harrison Retirement: -- To and from Salisbury. From David Halberstam, Clark Clifford, Moshe Decter (Conference on the Status of Soviet Jews), Wes Gallagher (President and General Manager, AP), Senator Hubert Humphrey, Peter Kihss (New York Times), Ben Kubasik (The New Yorker), Priscilla Johnson Macmillan, Herbert Matthews, 1973 (Box 552, Folder 6)
  - Rosenthal, A. M. 1973 (Box 552, Folder 7)
  - Board of Foreign Scholarships: Fulbright (Box 553, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous I: -- To and from Salisbury. From Sen Charles McC. Mathias Jr. (MD), Barbara Tuchman, Curtis Brown LtD., Charles Z. Wick (Director, USIA), E. Clifton Daniel, R. W. (Johnny) Apple (New York Times, London), Christopher Wren (New York Times, Beijing), Holt Rinehart and Winston, Ploughshares Fund, John Noble Wilford (New York Times), Harper and Row, American Philosophical Society, Adam Ulam (Director, Harvard Russian Research Center), Marshall Shulman (Director, Harriman Institute, Columbia University), Michael Salisbury (son), Joe Fox (Editor, Random House), Simon Michael Bessie (Cornelia and Michael Bessie ), Pantheon (Andre Shiffrin, et aL.), Encyclopaedia Britannica, Congress of Russian Americans, Mongolia Society, S. Frederick Starr (President, Oberlin College), Russell Baker, Stephen F. Cohen, Gunther Schuller (composer) -- Copy of Salisbury to Ira Glasser (ACLU). Some in Russian, 1984 (Box 553, Folder 6)
  - Travel, Italy, 1992, (Air Ticktes, Bills, Itenary, Invitations, Schedules, Correspondence ) (Box 660, Folder 6)
  - Clips: re Malenkov Named Premier 3/7/53, Malenkov Quits 7/8/55, Stalin Expose 3/56, Malenkov, Secret Speech, Stalin Riots Georgia, 1953-1956 (Box 554, Folder 1)
  - Clips, 1949-1950 (Box 554, Folder 2)
  - Moscow, 1949-1950, (Clips ) (Box 554, Folder 3)
  - Nixon: Russian and General News (old -- poor quality, very brittle, some stuck together), 1959, (Clips, Photocopies ) (Box 554, Folder 4)
  - Moscow, 1959, (Clips ) (Box 554, Folder 5)
  - Russia Series: Old -- brittle, some stuck together, 1959, (Photocopies ) (Box 554, Folder 6)
  - Sakharov Material re "International Conference in Honor of Andrei Sakharov" (schedule, Sakharov paper, "The responsibility of Scientists" -- in English etc.) (Box 554, Folder 7)
  - Vladimir Karpov Russia At War: Translated from Russian by Lydia Kmituk -- multiple versions, with differences in editing and format -- photocopied, (Photos, Mss. ) (Box 554, Folder 8)
  - America and Russia Today: Script for "2-hour evening special" (TV), from Second Street Films, 1980 (Box 555, Folder 9)
  - Soviet Union: -- USSR May Day Mongolia-Soviet Embassy, 1959 (Box 555, Folder 10)
  - Russia, 1954-1985 (Box 555, Folder 11)
  - Raisa Gorbachev By Kolkhoznovo Krest'ianstva: In Russian, published 1969, (Photocopy, Book ) (Box 555, Folder 12)
  - Mikhail S. Gorbachev An Intimate Biography1988: By the editors of Time magaazine, (Page Proofs, Photocopy ) (Box 556, Folder 13)
  - Abel Aganbegyan Letter, Photocopy, Books, Mss.: In Russian -- with to Salisbury from Cornelia and Michael Bessie Bessie, Nov 14, 1988 (Box 556, Folder 14)
  - Sergei Khrushchev Memoirs, Photocopy, Mss.: Of His Father, in Russian, 1989 (Box 556, Folder 15)
  - Moscow Art Theater, New York City, 1965 (Box 557, Folder 1)
  - RFE, Mongolia, 1964 (Box 557, Folder 2)
  - Eastern Europe: Satellites, late FBIS, RFE and Congressional, 1964, (Reports ) (Box 557, Folder 3)
  - Very Mixed Medley: To and from Salisbury. From Sydney Gruson (New York Times, London [1967]), Justice William O. Douglas, Warren Eason (Princeton, DepT. of Economics), Allen Dulles, James Reston, Arthur Hays Sulzberger, William Benton (Encyclopaedia Britannica), 1956-1957, (Letters, RFE Promotional Material ) (Box 557, Folder 4)
  - Souvenirs, Russia Trip Press Passes, Theatrical &amp -- Concert Programs, 1959 (Box 557, Folder 4A)
  - RFE: -- Some in Russian, 1963 (Box 557, Folder 5)
  - St. Anthony's College: From Conference on Soviet Literature, 1917-1962 (Oxford, July 1-8, 1962). Some papers in French, Russian, 1962, (Literature Meeting, Summer Papers ) (Box 558, Folder 6)
  - Yevtushenko Literary: -- Some in French, 1963 (Box 558, Folder 7)
  - Yevtushenko Literary: -- Selected Poems (preface in English). Some in Russian, 1962 (Box 559, Folder 8)
  - Literary &amp -- Arts, 1964-1965 (Box 559, Folder 9)
  - Yevtushenko Soviet Literary Copies of Novyi Mir [New World, Russian literary journal), #s 1 and 12, 1962. Some in Russian, 1962 (Box 559, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous: -- SU RFE, 1961 (Box 559, Folder 11)
  - Hungarian Refugees -- Including one of V. P. Nixon with refugee family, 1957-1959 (Box 560, Folder 1)
  - Features: -- Second Ave. (Yiddish Bohemian), Fifth Ave. Windows, Father Bissonette and Assumption Salisbury and (typescript with revisions) (Box 560, Folder 2)
  - Salisbury Tourism Story -- To and from Salisbury. 1961 (Box 560, Folder 3)
  - Soviet Journalists Material re visit of Soviet editors to US, May 1961 (Box 560, Folder 4)
  - New York Times Iran, 4 December 1961 (Box 560, Folder 5)
  - Iran: re project to establish hospital in Iran, etc., (Brochures, Letters ) (Box 560, Folder 6)
  - Arthur Miller, Marilyn Monroe Theater, 1957 (Box 560, Folder 7)
  - Biographic Data: Eisenhower, Nixon, [Kent] Cooper, Booth, 1955, (Dispatches, Memos, Notes ) (Box 561, Folder 8)
  - Tourism: -- Including from SeN. Kenneth Keating (NY), 1961 (Box 561, Folder 9)
  - Asian Countries: -- Japan, Sikkim, Burma, Thailand, India, 1966 (Box 561, Folder 10)
  - Central Committee of the Mongolian People's Revolutionary Party: to the XV Copngress of the MPRP," delivered by YU. Tsedenbal, First Secretary of the Central Committee of the MPRP-- bound copy, Ulan-Bator, 1966, (Report ) (Box 561, Folder 11)
  - Tibet, Sinkiang, 1964-1966 (Box 561, Folder 12)
  - Mongol Papers -- Mongolian RFE -- Some in Russian (Box 561, Folder 13)
  - Trofim Lysenko RFE Some in Russian, 1958, 1961 (Box 561, Folder 14)
  - Bordeaux: Mostly in French, 1973, (Brochures, Invitations, Maps, Magazines, Correspondence ) (Box 562, Folder 15)
  - Russia: -- Bolshoi Trip Ossia Trilling on Meyerhold 1958 -- Malenkov Obit. -- Moiseyev 1958 -- U. S. Exhibition 1959 and Ossia Trilling to New York Times Drama Editor, Ulanova, 1959 (Box 562, Folder 16)
  - Mongolia: -- Loose papers on the Directives of the XV Congress of MPRP on the Five-Year Plan of the Development of the National Economy and Culture of the MPR for 1966-1970," Delivered by D. Molomzhamts, Secretary of the Central Committee of the MPRP (Ulan-Bator, 1966) -- bound copy -- Some in Russian, 1966 (Box 562, Folder 17)
  - Soviet Tourism, 1961 (Box 562, Folder 18)
  - China, 1966 (Box 562, Folder 19)
  - China -- Deaths of Mao and Chou From Chinese Mission to the UN, 1976 (Box 563, Folder 1)
  - Soviet Union -- Free Turkestan Movement From Sino-Soviet/Turkestan and Soviet Embassy, 1969-1970 (Box 563, Folder 2)
  - China: -- Research Papers, News Digests, 1974-1975 (Box 564, Folder 3)
  - China: Sino-Soviet Cultural Revolution, 1966 (Box 565, Folder 4)
  - China: Soviet Embassy, 1960-1961 (Box 565, Folder 5)
  - China: -- CR, 1966, (News Digests, Journals ) (Box 565, Folder 6)
  - Chinese UN Mission, 1977 (Box 565, Folder 7)
  - Shook Up Schools and Neighborhood, 1957-1958, (Letters, Newspapers, Reports, School Yearbooks, Programs to Parents, Student Projects ) (Box 566, Folder 1)
  - Shook-Up Schools and Neighborhood -- Oiginal Stories, multiple copies, typescript with revisions, 1958 (Box 566, Folder 2)
  - Shook-Up Schools and Neighborhood -- To and from Salisbury. From Robert Moses, George Braziller, Irving Gitlin (DiR. of Public Afairs, CBS), Anatole Shub (The New Leader) (Box 566, Folder 3)
  - Crime and Juvenile Delinquency -- NYC Youth Board, including material from International Social Service, Catholic Charities Organizations, Child Welfare League of America, Jan 1960 (Box 567, Folder 4)
  - Youth Problems Outside NYC -- "Shook-Up" series from outline including from Janet Salisbury, Edmund G. Brown (California AtT. General) (Box 567, Folder 5)
  - Delinquency #1 -- From Dorothy Gordon, John B. Oakes (New York Times), Truda T. Weil (AssT. Superintendant, NYC Board of Education), William Jansen (NYC Superintendant of Schools), Iphigene Ochs Sulzberger, Edgar Schenck (Director, Brooklyn Museum), Robert Moses, Richard C. Lee (Mayor, New Haven, CT), Edward S. Silver (District Attorney, Kings County), Charles Cogen (President, NY Teachers Guild, AFL-CIO). Some in Russian (Box 567, Folder 6)
  - Delinquency #2 -- To and from Salisbury. From Richard C. Lee (Mayor, New Haven, CT), Peter Capra (Executive Director, Boys Club of NY) (Box 567, Folder 7)
  - Delinquency #3 -- re nutrition, from Everett C, Clinchy (Administrative President, World Brotherhood), Edward S. Silver (District Attorney, Kings County), Turner Catledge (, with to Catledge from Harold Levine, SR. Editor of National Affairs, Newsweek) (Box 567, Folder 8)
  - Delinquency (Box 567, Folder 9)
  - Juvenile Delinquency #3 -- To and from Salisbury. From Martha Finkler (Principal, Nathaniel Macon JHS, Brooklyn), Elmer Lower (Director of Operations, CBS News), Dial Press, Houghton Mifflin, George Braziller, Harper and Brothers (Evan Thomas), Gladwin Hill (New York Times, Los Angeles), Doubleday (Box 568, Folder 10)
  - Mr. Adams East Harlem Project, Aug 24, 1961, (Letter, Notes ) (Box 568, Folder 11)
  - Shook-Up Generation -- To and from Salisbury. Clinton Theater Lawsuit Threats and "Shook-Up" series from Arthuur Hays Sulzberger, from C. L. Sulzberger (New York Times, Paris) and copy of Salisbury to Robert Moses (Box 568, Folder 12)
  - The Zhukov -- Including Current Digest of the Soviet Press, 1954-58, 1969-71 and material re Zhukov's Greatest Battles (1969, with introduction by Salisbury) and Zhukov's (1971) from: Cass Canfield (Harper and Row), Perry Knowlton (President, Curtis Brown LtD.) (Box 568, Folder 13)
  - Names for Eastern Europes Mall: To Russia, Mongolia, 1959 & 1957, (Notebook, Notes ) (Box 568, Folder 14)
  - Russia Trip: Nixon, Mongolia, Pasternak, Khrushchev 5 spiral, some loose pp., 1959, (Notebooks, Notes ) (Box 568, Folder 15)
  - Council on Foreign Relations Trip to Japan: Salisbury/CFR, 1969 (Box 568, Folder 16)
  - The 900 Days: Miscellaneous chapters and pp., some typescript with corrections in pencil or ink, some photocopied and some multiple copies or versions -- From editorial assistant at Harper and Row, (Letter, Index Sheets, Early Drafts ) (Box 568, Folder 17)
  - The 900 Days I (Box 569, Folder 18)
  - The 900 Days II: -- From Anthony Lewis (New York Times, London), including 1 in French, 1 in Russian (Box 569, Folder 19)
  - The 900 Days III: -- Some in French, German, Russian, Danish. From Cass Canfield, Svetlana Alliluyeva (Box 569, Folder 20)
  - NYC Department of Sanitation, 1953, 1954 (Box 570, Folder 1)
  - Yonkers Series, 1955 (Box 570, Folder 2)
  - Yonkers: Chapter III, appears to refer to A Time of Change, (Notes ) (Box 570, Folder 3)
  - Yonkers Chapter III: Including from Yonkers Board of Education (Box 570, Folder 4)
  - [A Time of Change]: Chapter I: To Salisbury from, Janet Salisbury (1986), Peter Kihss (1983) (Box 570, Folder 5)
  - Manhatttan Story Chap III, typescript with corrections, probably carbon copy (Box 570, Folder 6)
  - Transport Series, 1959 (Box 570, Folder 7)
  - Soviet Farm Delegation, 1955, (Notebook ) (Box 570, Folder 8)
  - Balkans Series [some in Russian], 1957 (Box 570, Folder 9)
  - Balkans Series: "Our Public Schools" (Annual, NYC Superintendant of Schools) -- New York State Commissioner of Housing -- "Housing Responsibilities" (1956) -- "A Primer About Slums and Urban Renewal" (1958) -- NYC Department of Corrections Fifth Annual Report, 1958 -- "Voice of Concord", Concord Baptist Church of Christ, Brooklyn, 1957, (Notebooks, Annual Report ) (Box 570, Folder 10)
  - Balkan Series, 1957, (Clippings, Notes ) (Box 571, Folder 11)
  - Balkan Corespondence I: -- To and from Salisbury. Formerly loose papers, to New York Times editor -- From David C. Williams (Americans for Democratic Action), C. L. Sulzberger, Earl Johnson (United Press). Some in Polish (Box 571, Folder 12)
  - Balkan Corespondence II: -- To and from Salisbury. Copy by Hungarian Catholic League of America. From William Benton (Encyclopaedia Britannica), Jack Raymond (New York Times, Washington DC). -- Formerly loose papers and some in Bulgarian. (Box 571, Folder 13)
  - Business Cards, Notes, Miscellaneous Names, Scraps of Paper, 1966-1970 (Box 571, Folder 14)
  - Promo: Some in Japanese, 1970 (Box 571, Folder 15)
  - "Contacts in Cambodia", 1966-1968, (Notebooks, Notes, Names, Typed Sheet, Small Packets ) (Box 571, Folder 16)
  - Romanian Sculpture: Mara Basca b&w, various sizes, most labelled on back, Nov 15, 1967, (Letter, Photos ) (Box 571, Folder 17)
  - War Between Russia and China with poem in Russian. (Box 571, Folder 18)
  - Race Shook-Up, (Letter, Interview, Pamphlets, Reports, Notes ) (Box 572, Folder 19)
  - Shook-Up Including materials from Yorkville Youth Council, Jewish Board of Guardians [Correspondence] (Box 572, Folder 20)
  - Housing: Shook-Up to Salisbury, NYC Housing Authority data, excerpts from Congressional hearing testimony, (Letters, Notes ) (Box 572, Folder 21)
  - Schools: Mike Berger -- incident Shook-Up, (Interview, Pamphlets, Reports, Correspondence, Notes ) (Box 572, Folder 22)
  - General Shook-Up and "West Side Story" Playbill (Box 572, Folder 23)
  - Solutions Shook-Up series -- see also: Police -- Kennedy (Box 572, Folder 24)
  - Police: Shook-Up and other research, (Brochures, Press Releases, Interview, Reports, Notes ) (Box 572, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous: -- Shook-Up (loose papers) Salisbury. From NYC Youth Board, to Salisbury and progress from Robert McIver (NYC Juvenile Delinquency Evaluation Project): "Community Organization for Citizen Participation in Urban Renewal", Housing Association of Metropolitan Boston, et al., 1957 -- "Juvenile Violence in California", Citizens' Advisory Committee to the Attorney General on Crime Prevention, 2/21/58: "Teenage Gangs", NYC Youth Board, 1957 -- NYC Board of Education -- "All-Day Neighborhood Schools -- Directory of Evening High Schools, Summer Evening High Schools, Evening Trade Schools, Continuaiton Classes, 1957-58 (Box 572, Folder 26)
  - Juvenile Delinquency Evaluation Project, City College Progress: Interim #s III, V, VI, VIII (2 copies), IX, X, XI, XII, XIII, XIV, XVI -- Final I-III -- The Committee to Study the "600" Schools -- Alfred J. Kahn for the Citizens' Committee for Children of New York, InC. -- When Children Must be Committed (1960) -- For Children in Trouble (1957) -- First Principles in Planning Community Services to Deal with Children in Trouble (aricle, 1956) -- "Home Care and Housing Needs of the Aged", New York State Division of Housing, 1958, 3/23/58 -- No folders, BOUND REPORTS, PAMPHLETS, ETC., (Reprint, Report, Reports ) (Box 573)
  - Harvest of Despair: re "Firing Line" program on Ukrainian famine, 1932-33 (Salisbury a panelist), 1986, (Correspondence ) (Box 574, Folder 1)
  - Harvest of Despair, (Correspondence [II] ) (Box 574, Folder 2)
  - Stowe Science KFC Conference: Conferences on: Science and World Affairs -- International cooperation in Science -- Arms Control and Disarmament -- Official materials, (mostly handwritten), Salisbury summary (multiple copies or versions) -- The Atomic Scientists, September 1961, (Bulletin, Notes ) (Box 575, Folder 3)
  - Chicago, China KFC, 1966, (Correspondence, List of Participants, Papers, Abstracts, Publications ) (Box 575, Folder 4)
  - China-Soviet Materials Conference on US-China Relations, 1971, 1970-1971 (Box 576, Folder 5)
  - Sino-Soviet RFE Daily, May 1964, (Bulletins, Reports, Research ) (Box 576, Folder 6)
  - Soviet- China, RFE Daily: In French, 1963, (Newspaper, Published Material, Monograph ) (Box 576, Folder 7)
  - Sino-Soviet: Mongolia 2/1/65 to 6/78. RFE/RL, New York Times (Henry Tanner, Moscow to Sydney Gruson, NY), 1964-1978, (Letter, Published Material ) (Box 576, Folder 8)
  - China -- From Council on Foreign Relations. Some in Russian, 1973 (Box 577, Folder 9)
  - China: -- Printed Material, 1959 (Box 577, Folder 10)
  - China: -- Important Documents, Notes: Alsop, John Service Luncheon Talk, Lin Biao, Tuchman at Service Lunch, Dan Jacobs on Borodin Council on Foreign Relations working papers, on CCP Congress, NoV. 1973, 1973 (Box 577, Folder 11)
  - China -- Lindbeck Studies on US Training in China studies, Ed Clubb Studies, Ellsberg: The Quagmire Myth, Ford Foundation on China training, 1954-55 -- Studies of contemporary China, 1959 (Box 577, Folder 12)
  - Khrushchev and China: Salisbury summary and re CIA-- removed. American in Russia, and The Shook-Up Generation, both inscribed to Mother by Salisbury, 1962, (Books, Notes ) (Box 577, Folder 13)
  - China - Soviet (Box 578, Folder 1)
  - Ideology Khrushchev, China, Yugo (some in Russian), FBIS, RFE, 1962 (Box 578, Folder 2)
  - China - Russia, 1959-1961 (Box 579, Folder 3)
  - Sino-Russia and related -- Mongolia, Albania [some '61] and RFE. -- New York Times including from SeN. Mike Mansfield (Montana), with copy of Mansfield in Congressional Record, 1962-1963 (Box 579, Folder 4)
  - Telford Taylor The Price of Peace [I]: Edited, front material and pp. 1-278, Munich, (Photocopy, Mss. ) (Box 580, Folder 5)
  - Telford Taylor The Price of Peace [II]: pp. 279-333, 379-631, Munich (Box 580, Folder 6)
  - Telford Taylor The Price of Peace [III]: pp. 632-808, 857-995, Munich (Box 580, Folder 7)
  - Telford Taylor The Price of Peace [IV]: pp. 996-1102, 1317-1485, Munich (Box 580, Folder 8)
  - Telford Taylor The Price of Peace [V]: pp. 1486-1641 (end), Munich (Box 581, Folder 9)
  - Sakharov Manifesto II: In English with typescript introduction and by Salisbury. Multiple copies or versions, (Photocopy, Mss., Notes ) (Box 581, Folder 10)
  - Chalidze: w/ Valery Chalidze (Soviet dissident) -- corrected typescript with attached carbons, several pp. out of order separate duplicate copy, Jan 12, 1973, (Interview ) (Box 581, Folder 11)
  - Soviet Union: -- Soviet Chronology/ Lee Fuster: Photocopied and typescript (probably carbon ) pp. -- probably related to following folders, part of "The Soviet Union: The 50 Years", 1917-1967 (Box 581, Folder 12)
  - Soviet Union. Contributions For The Soviet Union: The 50 Years Edited by Salisbury [I] Hechinger, "The Child -- Pampered but Disciplined -- "Education: Triumphs and Doubts -- Grose, piece on religion (seems to be incomplete) -- Charlotte Curtis, "The Feminine Ideal: Equal but Separate -- Harold Schonberg, "Russian Music -- Hilton Kramer, "Art: A Return to Modernism -- Walter Sullivan, "The Death and Rebirth of a Science -- "The Akademgorodok -- A New Look in Soviet Science" (Box 581, Folder 13)